ANS Record Group 2: Curatorial, 1858-ongoing
ANS Archives
- Series 9: Howland Wood curator correspondence and other material, 1913-1937; 10 cubic feet (12 boxes)
  Wood, Howland, 1877-1938; Zabriskie, Andrew C. (Andrew Christian), 1853-1916; Morgan, J. P. (John Pierpont), 1867-1943; Robertson, Robert, 1869-1937; Robinson, John, 1846-1925; Ros, Giuseppe; Ramsden, Henry A., d. 1915; Titchener, Edward Bradford, 1867-1927; Canfield, Frederick A. (Frederick Alexander), 1849-1926; New Jersey Historical Society; American Journal of Numismatics; American Numismatic Society; D.O. Mills & Co. (Sacramento, Calif.); Rubbings (Visual works); Correspondence; Photographs; Notebooks; Reports; Indexes (Reference sources)
  - Box 1 of 12
    - A-Z (Zerbe), 1913-1919
    - A, 1918-1919
    - A, 1918-1919
    - Ae-Am, 1924-1929
    - An-Az, 1924-1929
    - A, 1930-1932
    - A, 1932
    - A, 1935
    - A, 1936
    - A, 1937
    - Abbott, Justin E., 1919-1922
    - Abram, N., 1924
    - Adams, E.H., 1919-1925
    - Adams, Edward D., 1921-1929
    - Adjutant General, New York, 1919-1926
    - Adjutant Generals, various states, 1920-1924
    - Allan, Herbert S., 1925
    - American Ambassador, London, 1918
    - American Book Company, 1923
    - American Defense Society, 1918
    - American District Telegraph Company, 1920
    - American Express Company, 1919-1924
    - American Field Service – See H.D. Sleeper, 1920
    - American Historical Review, 1925-1926
    - American Museum of Natural History, 1921-1926
    - American Numismatic Association, 1922-1928
    - American Red Cross, 1921
    - Antiquarian and Numismatic Society of Montreal, 1923
    - Applicants for Position in Coin Room, 1927
    - Arguelles, J.M., 1927
    - Avery Architectural League, 1917
    - B, 1913-1917
    - Ba-Be, 1921-1929
    - Bel-Bl, 1921-1929
    - Bn-Bt, 1916-1929
    - Bu-Bz, 1921-1929
    - B, 1930-1932
    - B, 1933-1934
    - B, 1934
    - B, 1935
    - B, 1935
    - B, 1936
    - B, 1937
    - Babut, A., 1922
    - Bailey, Banks and Biddle Company, 1919-1927
    - Baldwin, A.H. and Son, 1936-1937
    - Baldwin and Sons, A.H., 1920-1927
    - Baldwin, A.H., 1930-1932
    - Bartlett, N.J., 1918
    - Battenberg, Prince Louis of, 1916
    - Baumgard, Henry, 1925
    - Beals, Walter Burges, 1920-1923
    - Beatty, W. Gedney, 1921-1925
    - Beebe, L.M., 1918
    - Belden, Bauman, 1930-1931
    - Bellinger, Alfred, 1928
    - Belote, Theodore, Smithsonian, 1919-1928
    - Berlin and Jones Envelope Company, 1921
    - Bernays, Edward L., 1922
    - Blake, George H., 1921-1927
    - Bolender, M.H., 1929
    - Bolender, M.H., 1930-1932
    - Bolender, M.H., 1935-1937
  - Box 2 of 12
    - Bolton, Chas K., 1925
    - Bonner, Campbell, 1930-1931
    - Boring, Edwin G. – regarding Titchener’s death, 1927
    - Borum, Charles, 1922-1929
    - Boston Museum of Fine Arts, 1922
    - Boyd, F.C.C., 1921-1929
    - Boyd, F.C.C., 1936
    - Boyd, F.C.C., 1937
    - Boy Scouts of America, 1920
    - Brand, H.A., 1921-1922
    - Brenner, Judson, 1920-1922
    - Brett, Agnes Baldwin, 1921-1929
    - Brett, Agnes Baldwin, 1931, 1937
    - British Museum, 1914-1919
    - British Museum (John Allan), 1920-1927
    - British Numismatic Society, 1919-1926
    - Brown, C.J., 1920-1923
    - Brown, George F., 1920-1927
    - Brown, H.B., 1925
    - Bryant, L.E., 1928
    - Bucknill, John, 1924-1926
    - Bulkeley, Morgan G., 1917
    - Burlington, Massachusetts, Select Men of, 1919-1920
    - Burns Brothers Coal, 1920
    - C, 1913-1920
    - C, 1913-1920
    - C-Cg, 1919-1929
    - Ch-Cl, 1920-1929
    - Co-Cz, 1920-1928
    - C, 1930-1932
    - C, 1933-1934
    - C, 1935
    - C, 1936
    - C, 1937
    - Cahn, Adolph, 1924-1928
    - Campbell, William, 1928-1929
    - Cantor, L., 1922
    - Cardwell, L.A., 1920
    - Cary, A. Lucius, 1921
    - Cederlund, Ragnar, 1935
    - Central Hanover Bank, 1933
    - Central Hanover Bank, 1934
    - Central Hanover Bank, 1935
    - Central Hanover Bank, 1936
    - Central Hanover Bank, 1937
    - Cerney, Ernest, 1937
    - Chapman, S.H., 1920-1928
    - Charleston Museum, 1925-1926
    - Chase and Company (J.B. Chase), 1927
    - Chicago, State Bank of (Arthur L. Bowen), 1927-1928
    - Clapp, George H., 1937
    - Clark, T. James, 1927-1929
    - Clarke, Thomas B., 1924
    - Clausen, John, 1921-1922
    - Cleveland Museum of Art, 1922-1923
    - Cleveland Museum of Natural History, 1922
    - Collins, Lathrop, 1921
    - Collins, Lt. Ross F., 1920-1923
    - Colorplate Engraving Company, 1920
    - Comparette, T. Louis, 1916-1918
    - Comparette, T. Louis, 1919-1920
    - Comparette, T. Louis, 1921-1922
    - Connor, John M. Jr., 1921-1929
    - Connor, John M. Jr., 1922-1925
    - Consolidated Gas Company, 1908-1928
    - Cook, Mrs. Henry L. – also Caldwell Company, Insignia File, First Families of Virginia, Order of, 1920
    - Coon, Carleton (Peabody Museum), 1935
    - D, 1915-1920
    - D-Deu, 1920-1929
    - Dev-Duf, 1920-1929
    - Dug-Dz, 1920-1929
    - D, 1930-1932
  - Box 3 of 12
    - D, 1933-1934
    - D, 1935
    - D, 1936
    - D, 1937
    - Dalley, William T., 1926-1928
    - De Saint Phalle, Fal, 1924
    - Dewey, William (Westchester County Coin Club), 1935
    - DeVinne Press, 1925
    - Drowne, Henry R., 1920-1927
    - Duffield, Frank G., 1921-1928
    - Dummer, Mrs. F., 1921
    - E, 1914-1930
    - E-Eld, 1920-1929
    - Elf-Ez, 1920-1929
    - E, 1933
    - E, 1936
    - E, 1937
    - Eaton, Commodore W.C., 1920
    - Egger, Brüder, 1928
    - Eidlitz, Robert, 1921-1934
    - Eidlitz, Robert, 1930-1931
    - Eklund, Ole P., Collection, 1933-1934
    - Eklund, Ole P., 1937
    - Elder, Thomas, 1909-1929, 1934 (for Elder, see also Roh, C.F, 1921-1924)
    - Ellis, Ralph, 1923
    - Ellsworth, James W., 1920-1922
    - Enhaus and Son, Wiliam H., 1920
    - F, 1913-1919
    - F, 1915-1932
    - F-Fi, 1921-1929
    - Fl, 1920-1927
    - Fo-Fr, 1922-1929
    - Fri-Fz, 1922-1926
    - F, 1933
    - F, 1936
    - F, 1937
    - Falls, De Witt Clinton, 1920-1928
    - Falls, De Witt Clinton, 1934-1935
    - Ferris, H.B., 1925
    - Field, William B.O., 1920-1927
    - Finland, Consulate General, 1925
    - First Families of Virgina, 1920
    - Fisher, Charles H., 1928
    - Folsom and Company Engraving, 1920-1923
    - Ford, Edwin, 1923
    - Frank, A., 1932-1933
    - Franklin, Clarence P., 1920
    - French Mint, 1922-1923
    - Frey, Albert R., 1920-1926
    - Fried, N., 1924
    - G-Go, 1920-1929
    - Gr-Gz, 1920-1929
    - G, 1929-1932
    - G, 1933-1934
    - G, 1935
    - G, 1936
    - Garrett, John W., 1920-1929
    - Geist, Emil, 1925
    - Gibbs, H.D., 1923-1928
    - Gibbs, H.D., 1935-1936
    - Gibbs, H.D., 1937
    - Gifford, Carleton S., 1921-1927
    - Gifford, Carleton S., 1937
    - Gilbert, L.L., 1922
    - Gilmore, George W., 1922-1929
  - Box 4 of 12
    - Gillingham, Harrold E., 1918-1926
    - Gillingham, Harrold E., 1927-1934
    - Gillingham, Harrold E., 1935-1937
    - Gimbel Brothers, 1924
    - Gleaner, The, 1921
    - Glendining and Company, England, 1922
    - Gordon, John, 1918-1925
    - Gould, W.B., 1923
    - Guttag Brothers, 1925-1929
    - Guttag Brothers, 1930-1935
    - Guttag, Julius, 1937
    - H-He, 1920-1928
    - Hi-Hl, 1920-1928
    - Ho-Hz, 1920-1928
    - H, 1930-1932
    - H, 1933-1934
    - H, 1935
    - H, 1936
    - H, 1936
    - H, 1937
    - Haines, Howard, 1930-1931
    - Hall, James S., 1922
    - Hall-Marvin Company, 1921
    - Harlow, A.F., 1925
    - Harris, Mrs. Edward M., 1920
    - Harrison, John T., 1928
    - Harrison, McVeigh, 1924
    - Hart, W.O., 1925-1929
    - Hazelton, Alan, 1930-1932, 1934
    - Heal, S.S., 1920-1927
    - Heliotype Company, 1920-1927
    - Henderson, Dr. J.M., 1921-1928
    - Herzfeld, Max, 1920
    - Hesslein, William, 1922-1927
    - Hesslein, William, 1928-1929
    - Hesslein, William, 1929-1934
    - Het Koniklijk Nederlandish Genootschap, 1921
    - Hetrich, Dr. George, 1923-1927
    - Heye, George (Museum of the American Indian), 1922-1926
    - Hill, G.G. (British Museum), 1917
    - Hill, H.L., 1928-1929
    - Hoernle, R.F. and Sophie, 1920
    - Holmbers Mythandel, D., 1927-1929
    - Holstein, Otto, 1927
    - Honduras, Coins and Money of, 1921
    - Hopkins, A.A., 1920-1926
    - Horstman, William H. and Company, Uniforms and Flags, 1919-1929
    - House of Representatives, Grant Medal and Hayes Coin, 1922
    - I, 1917-1927
    - I, 1930-1932
    - I, 1933-1936
    - I, 1936-1937
    - Indelli and Conforti Company, 1921
    - India, Numismatic Society of, n.d.
    - Indian Peace Medals, 1926
    - Indian Medals – Chapman Letter, 1920
    - Irving Studios, 1920
    - J, 1913-1932
    - J, 1920-1930
    - J, 1933-1934
    - J, 1935
    - J, 1936
  - Box 5 of 12
    - Jones, John F., 1937
    - K, 1915-1926
    - K, 1930-1932
    - K, 1933-1934
    - K, 1935
    - K, 1936
    - K, 1937
    - Kegan, Paul – Trench Company, 1920-1921
    - Kilborn, L.S., 1923
    - Kip, Rudolf, 1926
    - Kohlhammer, W., 1923
    - Kohler, Rudolph, 1925-1928
    - Kohn and Son, Theodore A., 1920-1929
    - Kovessey, Albin de, 1922
    - Kraus, Franz, 1928-1929
    - Kunz, George F., 1920-1926
    - Kronfeld, Saunders and Company, 1911-1928
    - L, 1913-1921
    - La-Le, 1923-1931
    - Lh-Ly, 1923-1929
    - L, 1930-1932
    - L, 1933-1934
    - L, 1935
    - L, 1936
    - L, 1937
    - Landa, Everado, 1928-1929
    - Langdon, William C., 1924-1928
    - Le Blanc, John F., 1920-1921
    - Lees, Hugh – see Victoria Cross, F.A. Bland, Major R. Stewart, 1921
    - Lemcke and Buechner – now Westermann Company, see file under W
    - Leve, A.A., 1921-1925
    - Levis, H.C., 1921-1929
    - Lichtenstein, Alfred F., 1919-1920
    - Little, E.Z., 1925-1928
    - Liveright, Frank I., 1919-1931
    - Lloyd, A.H., 1923-1927
    - Lombard, J.W., 1918
    - Lord, A.L., 1920-1922
    - Lynn Public Library, 1918-1919
    - M, 1914-1929
    - Mi-Mz, 1920-1929
    - McA-McF, 1930
    - McL, 1930-1931
    - M, 1930-1932
    - M, 1933-1934
    - M, 1933-1934
    - M, 1935
    - M, 1936
    - M, 1937
    - Mabbott, Thomas Ollive, 1935
    - Mabbott, Thomas Ollive, 1937
    - Marinidin, Ritchie, 1932
  - Box 6 of 12
    - McLachlan, R.W., 1920-1921
    - Medallic Art Company, 1922-1928
    - Medallic Art Company, 1936
    - Mehl, B. Max, 1910-1928
    - Merritt, Ferris P., 1920-1924
    - Merzbacher Nachf, Eugen
    - Metts, General J. Van B., 1920 – see North Carolina Service Medal World War I
    - Meyer, N.S., 1918
    - Mexican Academy, (Señor Manuel Romero de Terreros), 1931
    - Miller, Emma, 1920, see Miller-Ryder, Ryder-Miller, Goodbody and Company
    - Minassian, Kirkor, 1927
    - Minister of Militia and Defense, 1921
    - Mint, The Birmingham, 1930-1931
    - Morgan, Harold, 1922
    - Mosher, Stuart, 1937
    - Müller and Sohn, 1927-1928
    - Museum Exhibit – ANS Traveling Exhibit, 1926-1927
    - N, 1916-1918, 1932
    - N, 1922-1928
    - N, 1930-1932
    - N, 1933-1934
    - N, 1936
    - N, 1937
    - Nashville War Medal, 1920 – See Foster, Edgar
    - National Committee on Awards, Red Cross, 1920
    - Navy Department, Bureau of Navigation, 1920 – See Bailey, Banks and Biddle, Roosevelt, F.D.
    - Newcomb, Howard R., 1921-1926
    - Newcomer, Waldo, 1920-1929
    - Newell, Edward T., 1918, 1919(?), 1927-1935
    - New Jersey Historical Society (Canfield Collection), 1930-1931
    - Noe, Sydney P., 1920-1929
    - Noe, Sydney P., 1936
    - Norman, James C., 1925
    - Norris, F.A., 1922-1925
    - Noury Bey, Osman, 1922
    - O, 1921-1929
    - O, 1930-1932
    - O, 1933-1934
    - O, 1933-1935
    - O, 1936
    - O, 1936-1937
    - Oakland Public Museum, 1920
    - Odenwelder, George M., 1920
    - Office, J.E., 1920
    - Oliver, O., 1919
    - Pa-Pe, 1920-1929
    - Pf-Po, 1920-1929
    - Pr-Pz, 1920-1929
    - P, 1923-1932
    - P, 1929-1932
    - P, 1933-1934
    - P, 1935
    - P, 1936
    - P, 1937
    - Parris, Edward L. Jr. (Paris, Maine), 1932-1933
    - Part-time, Bureau of, 1926
    - Perez, Gilbert, 1919-1927
    - Perez, Gilbert, 1937
    - Philippine Constabulary, 1923-1927
    - Pheonix Engraving Company, 1921-1922 (see Watts, A.O.)
    - Pond, Shepard (Boston Numismatic Society), 1935
    - Pond, Shepard (Boston Numismatic Society), 1936
    - Pond, Shepard (Boston Numismatic Society), 1937
    - Pope, Mrs. James E., 1919, 1921
    - Post Office, 1921-1922
    - Porter, Benjamin, 1923
    - Pradeau, A.F., 1930-1937
    - Pradeau, A.F., 1936
    - Powell, William R., 1920-1929
    - Pratt, Dr. Joseph Hyde (Confederate Half Dollar of 1861), 1920
    - Prince, Bradford, 1921
    - Publicity (Army-Navy Exhibition, ca. 1917), 1915-1920
    - Q, 1930-1932
    - Q, 1933-1934
    - Queensborough, Lord, 1922-1923
    - Quigley, Margery, 1921
    - R, 1913-1921
    - Ra-Re, 1920-1929
    - Rh-Ri-Ro, 1920-1929
    - Ru-Rz, 1920-1929
  - Box 7 of 12
    - R, 1929-1934
    - R, 1931-1934
    - R, 1930, 1934-1935
    - R, 1935-1936
    - R, 1937
    - Radin, Herman, 1921
    - Raymond, Wayte, 1920-1930
    - Raymond, Wayte, 1934
    - Raymond, Wayte, 1936
    - Raymond, Wayte, 1935-1937
    - Rea, C.D., 1925-1926
    - Reach, A.L, Textile Company, 1921
    - Reilly, John, Jr., 1918-1929
    - Robertson, Robert, 1921-1928
    - Robertson, Robert – Death of and application of William L. Clark for his position, 1937
    - Robinson, Edward, 1910-1920
    - Robinson, Edwin P., 1920-1929
    - Robinson, John (Peabody Museum), 1921-1925
    - Roh, C.F., 1921-1924 (includes two Thomas Elder letters, 1924, possibly misfiled, in which he complains of being overlooked in favor of other dealers)
    - Roosevelt Memorial Association, 1921-1926
    - Ros, Guiseppi, 1917-1927
    - Rosenaum, George, 1918
    - Ross, David, 1922
    - Ruditsky, Nat P., 1923-1925
    - Rudnick, Perry N., 1920, 1929
    - Ryder, Hillyer, 1920-1924
    - S, 1914-1919
    - Sa-Se, 1921-1929
    - Sh-Sp, 1921-1929
    - Sq-St, 1921-1929
    - Su-Sz, 1921-1929
    - S, 1930-1934 (1 of 2)
    - S, 1930-1934 (2 of 2)
    - S, 1935
    - S, 1936
    - S, 1937 (1of 2)
    - Salle, Andre, 1920-1929
    - St. Louis Stamp and Coin Company, 1922-1928
    - St. Louis Stamp and Coin Company, 1930-1933
    - Saltus, J. Sanford, 1918-1923
    - Savage, M.F., 1926
    - Scientific American, 1920
    - Schulman, J., 1918-1928
    - Schulman, J., 1930-1934
    - Schulman, J., 1935
    - Schulman, J., 1936
    - Schultz, Norman, 1920
    - Seaby, B.A., 1930-1934
    - Seaby, B.A., 1935
  - Box 8 of 12
    - Sears, Elmer S., 1919-1929
    - Smith, David Eugene, 1922-1925
    - Smith, Elliot, 1913-1928
    - South-West News Company, 1920-1922
    - Sperr, P.L., 1924
    - Spink & Son, 1921-1929
    - Spink & Son, 1930-1934
    - Spink & Son, 1936
    - Spink & Son, 1935-1937
    - Skilton, A.G., 1925
    - Starosselsky, V.D., 1921-1938
    - Starr, Floyd T., 1920-1925
    - Steinman, Leland (Pacific Coast Numismatic Society), 1920-1921
    - Stejneger, L. (Smithsonian), 1919
    - Stearns, Foster, 1922-1926
    - Stevens and Brown, 1922
    - Stephenson, W.R.C., 1922-1923
    - Stewart and Company, 1917
    - Stokes, I.N. Phelps, 1925-1926
    - Storer, Malcolm, 1920-1927
    - Swanson, Jonathon, 1922-1926
    - Swedish Red Cross, 1921
    - T, 1918-1919
    - T, 1923-1929
    - T, 1928-1929
    - T, 1929-1934
    - T, 1936
    - T, 1935-1937
    - Tapp, Garold W. (Bechtler coin press, sold to Julius Guttag, then donated to ANS), 1926-1928
    - Tefft, Carl E., 1924
    - Titchener, E.B., 1922-1927 (1 of 2)
    - Titchener, E.B., 1922-1927 (1 of 2)
    - Titchener, E.B., 1922-1927 (2 of 2)
    - Torrey, R.H., 1921 (see New York Evening Post)
    - Toscano, C., 1922
    - Tracey Woodward, A.M., 1931
    - Treasury Department, 1933-1934
    - Treasury Department, 1935
    - Trenton Trust Company, 1928-1929
    - U, 1919
    - U, 1924-1928
    - U, 1930-1934
    - U, 1935-1937
    - U, 1936
    - Union Trust Company, 1916
    - Union Trust Company, 1917
    - Union Trust Company, 1918
    - United States Army, 1918-1919
    - United States Army, 1928-1929
    - United States Army and Navy Recognition Exhibition, 1918
    - United States Marine Corps, 1918, 1923
    - University of Michigan, 1922
    - United States Treasury Department, 1927-1928
    - United States Mint, 1920-1928
    - United States Navy, 1918-1921
    - United States Shipping Board, 1918
    - V, 1913-1919
    - V, 1923-1929
    - V, 1936
    - V, 1935-1937
    - Valentine, W.H., 1919-1928
    - Valentine, D.W., 1930-1934
    - Vanderpoel, George B., 1919
    - Veterans of Foreign Wars, 1924-1925
    - Victory Medals, 1923
    - Voetter, Thomas W., 1920-1925
    - Vreeland, Nehemiah, 1920-1927
    - Wa-Wh, 1922-1929
    - Wi-Wo, 1922-1929
    - Wr-Wz, 1922-1929
  - Box 9 of 12
    - W, 1929-1934 (1 of 2)
    - W, 1929-1934 (2 of 2)
    - W, 1933-1934
    - W, 1935-1937
    - W, 1936
    - W, 1937
    - Walker Engraving Company, 1918-1922
    - Walker, John (British Museum), 1935-1937
    - Wanamaker, John, 1921, 1928
    - War Medals, 1919-1922
    - War Trade Board, 1918-1919
    - Ware, Ivan H. (Canton Christian College), 1924
    - Webber, Paine, 1930-1933
    - Wells, T. Tileston, 1918
    - Wernstrom, Ernest R. 1921-1922
    - Western Ontario, University of, 1928
    - What’s Going on in Greater New York (The Weekly Magazine of City News), 1911-1922
    - Wheeler, A.L. (American Journal of Archaeology), 1921
    - Wheeler, Horace L., 1915-1929
    - Wheeler, Horace L., 1925
    - Whicher, George Meason, 1918-1929
    - Whipple, Allen, 1913-1916
    - White, Alfred T., 1918-1919
    - White, Edward A., 1920
    - Whitehead, R.B., 1920-1923
    - Whitehead and Hoag Company, 1920-1927
    - Williamson Paper Company, 1922
    - Williamson Paper Company, 1922
    - Wing, George C., 1921-1927
    - Wise and Ottenberg, 1923-1925
    - Wood, Casey, 1932-1935
    - Wood, Casey – Larins correspondence, 1926-1934
    - Wood, Howland (Personal), 1927-1932
    - Wood, Howland (Personal), 1934-1937
    - Wood, Howland (Personal), 1936
    - Woodward, A.M. Tracey, 1921-1926
    - World Book Company, 1921-1929
    - World War Medals, 1924-1925
    - Wormser, Moritz, 1920-1929
    - Wright, E.E., 1920-1921
    - Wright, Nelson, 1922-1929
    - Wulfing, John M. (Gildehaus, Wulfing and Company), 1921-1927
    - Wyllie, Robert E. (War Department), 1920-1921
    - Wyllie, Robert E. (War Department), 1920-1921
    - Wyman, Arthur C., 1921-1928
    - Wyman, Arthur C., 1932
    - X, 1921
    - Xerri, Emmanuele, 1920– see also George A. Laurence, Valetta Museum, American Counsel, Malta
    - Y, 1920-1928
    - Y, 1930-1933
    - Y, 1935-1937
    - Yale Publishing Association, 1922
    - Yale University Press, 1924-1929
    - Young Men’s Christian Association, 1918
    - Z, 1929, 1932, 1937
    - Zabriskie, Andrew C.
    - Zerbe, Farran, 1920-1928
    - Zerbe, Farran, 1930-1934
    - Zucchi, Mario, 1935, 1937
  - Box 10 of 12 - Notebooks
    - Notebook: Correspondence and Notes on Bull and Horse Indian Series, 1927
    - Notebook: Notes on Bull and Horseman Series II (with coin photographs)
    - Notebook: Notes on Coinage of British East India Company
    - Notebook: Notes on Coinage of British East India Company
    - Notebook: Indian Journals
  - Box 11 of 12 - Research Files
  - Box 12 of 12 - Reports and Medals
    - Curator Reports, 1913-1914
    - Committee Reports, 1915-1918
    - Curator Reports, 1916-1927
    - Curator Reports, 1927
    - American Medals, 1918-1921
    - Indian Peace Medals, 1917 (1 of 4)
    - Indian Peace Medals, 1917 (2 of 4)
    - Indian Peace Medals, 1917 (3 of 4)
    - Indian Peace Medals, 1917 (4 of 4)
- Series 10: George C. Miles curator correspondence, research materials, and lectures, 1933 - 1974; 3 cubic feet (4 boxes)
  Visigoth card file found in Robert Hoge’s office, April 2013
  Miles, George Carpenter, 1904-1975; Correspondence; Lectures; Research notes; Photographs
  The leading Islamic numismatist of his generation, George C. Miles (1904-1975) first came to the ANS in October 1937 as Research Assistant in Muhammadan Numismatics. Earlier that year, Miles had earned his doctorate in Oriental languages from Princeton University, where he had also earned his A.B. in 1926 and M.A. in 1930. From 1937 to 1938, Miles studied the Society's Islamic coin collection, verifying earlier work by Howland Wood and publishing his thesis as the magisterial Numismatic History of Rayy, which was issued in 1938 by the ANS as the second monograph in its Numismatic Studies series. After teaching at Princeton University and serving in the U.S. Navy during World War II, Miles returned to the ANS in 1946, where he initially served as Curator for Islamic Coins and studied the extensive collection of coins that Archer M. Huntington had donated to the Hispanic Society of America. The results of Miles' research on this collection were subsequently published in the ANS's Hispanic Numismatic Series. In 1954, Miles succeeded Sydney P. Noe as Chief Curator for the ANS, a position he maintained until 1969. In 1966, Miles was also named Executive Director of the ANS, a position he retained until his retirement in 1972. Miles also served as Secretary from 1966 through 1968. During his lifetime, Miles published 16 books and more than 75 articles. Miles also received numerous honors and awards, including the ANS's Archer M. Huntington Medal Award (1949), and medals of the Hispanic Society of America and Royal Numismatic Society (1957). Miles was a member of the American Philosophical Society, the Board of Scholars of Dumbarton Oaks, the Bureau of the International Numismatic Commission, and the Executive Committee of the Encyclopedia of Islam. In addition, Miles held honorary membership in the Société Française de Numismatique, the Société Belge de Numismatique, the Royal Numismatic Society, the Institut d'Egypte, and the Academies of Cordoba and Madrid. George Miles died on October 15, 1975, at the age of 71.
  Contains correspondence, research materials, and outlines and texts of lectures. The correspondence files (1933-1973), some of which predate Miles’s employment at the American Numismatic Society in 1946, mostly have to do with his scholarly work on Islamic coins, and include discussions of coins among colleagues and collectors, including some materials under consideration for the ANS collections. In the correspondence with Erich Schmidt (1936-1964), there are items pertaining to his work and management at an expedition camp at the site of the ancient Persian city of Rayy (Schmidt, 1936-1964), which resulted in the monograph Numismatic History of Rayy (1938), Miles’s first major contribution to the field. Research materials (1934-1974, bulk 1966-1974) consist of notes and photographs (including film negatives) of Islamic coins and objects, and note cards pertaining to Rayy and listing significant Islamic persons. Also present are outlines and the text of lectures Miles’s gave at various places (1946-1973). Though many have to do with Islamic collecting, there is a broader range of subjects covered in the lectures, including numismatics as a field of study (ANS, 1955), the role of coins in history (University of Buffalo, 1957), the role of numismatics in archaeology (Madison, Chicago, Montclair, 1963-1965), and numismatic crossroads (ANS, 1952). There are also photographs of Egyptian weighs, photographs of an Abu Sa’id coin, and pasted plates of A Catalog of the Palace Collection of Ancient Coins and Bronzes by Imperial Order, by Shizheng, et al. In addition, there is a card file of references and notes used for the preparation of his The Coinage of The Visigoths of Spain: Leovigild to Achila II, 1952.
  - Box 1 of 5 - Correspondence
    - Abgarians, Mesrob T.
    - Album, Stephen
    - Andres, T.
    - Artuk, Ibrahim
    - Awad, Heneri A.